

■ eleanor.em.cs@gmail.com | 🖀 eleanorm.info | 🖸 eleanor-em

## Summary.

I am a Master of Science (Computer Science) student at the University of Melbourne researching applied cryptography with Vanessa Teague. I have been a programmer for years, and am passionate about education, security, and privacy. Research interests include zero-knowledge proofs, authenticated data structures, and multiparty computation.

### **Education**

**University of Melbourne** Parkville VIC 3010

M.Sc. (COMPUTER SCIENCE) 2019-present B.Sc. (MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS) 2015-2018 DIPLOMA IN INFORMATICS 2015-2018

### **Experience**

### **University of Melbourne**

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jul 2019 - Present

- · Working with Prof. Shanika Karunasekera to develop and deploy a large distributed cloud-based system for data collection and analytics. The project allows large volumes of data (e.g., from social media) to be categorised by topic and analysed for patterns.
  - Responsibilities include finding and fixing issues, as well as developing new features and system monitoring scripts.
- · Assisted the security research group with grant applications.
- · Working with Dr Olya Ohrimenko on attacks against differentially private mechanism implementations.

#### **Blueprint for Free Speech**

**DEVELOPER LIAISON** Jul 2019 - Present

- Created a revived GitHub presence and website for the Ricochet end-to-end encrypted chat service operating over Tor.
- Helped update the C++ codebase and installation scripts to work with the latest versions of Tor and operating systems.

#### **University of Melbourne**

HEAD TUTOR (OBJECT-ORIENTED SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT)

Jul 2016 - Present

- · Managed the tutoring team for a core subject with hundreds of students, liaising between students, tutors, and lecturers.
- · Developed major assignments for students, including specifications, marking criteria, and testing methodology.
- Delivered one to two lectures per semester on software tools and alternative paradigms while also teaching two to three tutorials per week.
- Excellence in Tutoring Award (2017), School of Computing and Information Systems

# Writing.

(Authors listed alphabetically.)

Eleanor McMurtry, Olivier Pereira, Vanessa Teague. When is a test not a proof? To appear in ESORICS 2020.

Xavier Boyen, Chris Culnane, Kristian Gjøsteen, Thomas Haines, Eleanor McMurtry, Ronald Rivest, Peter Ryan, Vanessa Teague. Verifiable Remote Voting with Paper Assurance. In Submission.

Chris Culnane, Eleanor McMurtry, Robert Merkel, Vanessa Teague. Tracing the challenges of COVIDSafe. Blog post

### **Honors & Awards**

Student Registration Grant, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy

Oakland, California,

U.S.A.

### Presentation

**CSides** Canberra, Australia

SPEAKER

SPEAKER

· Presented an introduction to cryptography and formal notions of security.

### **OWASP Melbourne Chapter Meetup**

Melbourne, Australia

July 2020

June 2020

• Presented an in-depth exploration of the COVIDSafe mobile app, focusing on the root causes of the issues with its application security.

ELEANOR MCMURTRY · CV **SEPTEMBER 11, 2020**